

Johannesburg, South Africa

■ exec@sett.sh | 🕯 sett.sh | 🖸 sw00 | 🖹 sw00 | 🔰 @settface | 😉 sett.wai

Summary

"Ops-minded" software engineer with 6+ years professional experience as a consultant on many different projects and domains, all over the world: from web development to distributed back-end systems; non-profit social development, health and media to retail industry and corporate banking. Has a passion for continuous delivery, open source and the "developer experience". A nerd who cares deeply about craftsmanship and meaningful work.

Though initially pursuing an interest in game development, gained a lot more experience in web development as an autodidact then joined a software consultancy (Alacrity), attracted by opportunity to work on a wide breadth of projects and technologies. Later found himself at Thought-Works where a lot of learning, travel and growth took place. There, Sett was quickly pushed into various technical leadership roles in a short career, based on high technical aptitude and organisation's needs.

Experience

Self-employed

South Africa

Technical Consultant

May 2018 - Present

- Contract work for small company bootstrapping their product (JavaScript, NodeJS)
- · Piecework as a Software Engineer under FoldLeft Consulting for undisclosed client. (Java, Apache Kafka)
- · Enrolled in BScHons Computing at UNISA. Subjects: Research, Ontology Engineering, Machine Learning, Logic Programming

ThoughtWorks

South Africa, Uganda, USA, Brazil,

Kenya

CONSULTANT/SENIOR/LEAD DEVELOPER

Apr. 2013 - Dec 2017

- Built project team and laid technical foundations, practices and software delivery approach to replace legacy corporate banking integration in large SA Bank. (Spring Cloud, OpenShift) 7 months
- · Pursued and led the development of app for securities trading over USSD in Kenya (ASP.NET Core)- 3 months
- Implemented features, improved software development on a large team creating flagship Point of Sale (P.O.S.) platform for large US Retailer (iOS WebView, AngularJS, Spring, Microservices) 11 months
- Assisted in technical approach and the development of a greenfield Counter Human-Trafficking system in Uganda (DropWizard with bespoke front-end) - 3 months
- Provided technical leadership on an Anti-counterfeit Medicine verification system over SMS, deployed across Africa (Django, RabbitMQ, Mongo, Vumi) - 14 months
- Contributed to OpenStack testing framework for large ISP in the US, as part of Quality Engineering team. (Python) 6 months

Alacrity Technologies Pty Ltd

Johannesburg, South Africa

INTERN/JUNIOR DEVELOPER

May 2011 - Oct. 2012

- Built a prototype mobile web app for booking boardrooms (Play! framework, BackboneJS)
- Maintained/extended legacy ASP.NET (VB.NET) application for training fund trustees at a large financial services company. Introduced version control and modern web development practices there.
- Sole developer of online web portal and mobile web app to allow customers to view their pension fund statements online for above-mentioned company (ASP.NET MVC4, JQuery Mobile)

Education

UP(University of Pretoria)

Pretoria, South Africa

B.IS IN MULTIMEDIA

Feb. 2006 - Apr. 2010

• A combination of Computer Science, Multimedia and Visual Design culminating in Game Development

Skills___

Languages Python, Java, NodeJS, C#, Shellscript(Bash)

Frameworks Django, AngularJS, Spring, Express, DropWizard, ASP.NET

Backend RabbitMQ, MongoDB, Kafka, Nginx, Caddy **DevOps** Ansible, Chef, Docker, ELK, OpenShift, AWS

Practices Automation, Pair Programming, TDD, Continuous Delivery, Microservices, Infrastructure as Code, Domain Driven Design

Tools Vim, IntelliJ, Git, Vagrant/Docker, CI (GoCD, Jenkins, ConcourseCI, Bamboo)

Dabbles in... Go, Elm, Prolog

Natural Languages English, Afrikaans, Burmese

SEPTEMBER 11, 2018 SETT WAI · CURRICULUM VITAE